每天  我们都会做交易
Every day, every one of us makes a trade.
一支铅笔换一支钢笔
A pencil for a pen.
一个苹果换一个橘子
An apple for an orange.
一支舞换一个微笑
A dance for a smile.
只有莱顿先生能看
For Mr. Layton's eyes only,.
但这些交易并不总是按计划进行
But these trades don't always go the way you plan.
你给的比收到的多  条款改变
You give more than you get. The terms change.
最后不得不和自己交易
You end up having to trade with yourself.
我把我的未来都押在了一次交易上
I staked my future on a single trade.
跟他一起生活换取列车上的一个位置
A life with him for a place on this train.
已经循环了19圈
It's been 19 revolutions.
无论我走了多远  我早该知道
No matter how far I travelled, I should have known
威尔福德会找到我
Wilford would find me.
在雪国列车上
On Snowpiercer...
1034节车厢
1,034 cars long.
雪国列车
第二季 第四集
"单笔交易"
我跟奥德丽说了你想见她
I told Audrey you wanted to see her.
很好  还有呢
Good, and?
威尔福德揭开了很多旧伤疤
Well, Wilford opens a lot of old wounds,
别为难她
so just go easy on her.
你好啊  早上好
Hello there. Good morning.
-早  露丝  -扎拉
- Morning, Ruth. - Zarah.
恭喜了  莱顿先生
Well, congratulations, Mr. Layton.
今早交易进行得很顺利
Trade went off without a hitch this morning,
这是给你的
and this is for you personally.
写了什么
Well?
威尔福德先生提出
Mr. Wilford's offering treatment
要治疗我们的冻伤病人
to our frostbite patients--
他那丑陋冷冻人的受害者
victims of his big, ugly, Coldman.
海德伍德医生夫妇
Oh, from the Doctors Headwood.
这是个慷慨的提议  你说是吗
That's a generous offer, wouldn't you say?
不尽然
Not exactly.
谢谢  辛苦了
I appreciate that. Thank you.
冻伤治疗
Frostbite treatment--
你觉得这能帮到乔茜吗
are you thinking it could help Josie?
我觉得这能帮到我们的14个冻伤病人  拜
Think we have 14 frostbite patients it could help. Bye.
拜
Bye.
我没睡
I'm not asleep.
雪国列车工程师今天
Snowpiercer Engineers launched
发射了他们的气候仪器
their climate instruments today.
是的  跟梅兰妮合作的上行线
Oh, yes, the great uplink with Melanie.
要是只有静默  没有联系呢
What if there's just silence but no contact at all?
那她就会像你说的那样冻死
Then she froze to death exactly as you said.
很扣人心弦  对吗
Quite the cliffhanger, isn't it?
-他说什么  -你想要什么
- What's he say? - What do you want?
莱顿先生觉得我想要什么
What does Mr. Layton think I want?
我知道  你的情人  奥德丽小姐
I know--your paramour, Miss Audrey.
情人  你在看什么小说
Oh, "paramour." What novel are you reading?
你怎么不邀请她过来
Why don't you just invite her over already?
因为我想要的
Because what I want
比这有意思多了
is much more fun.
到雪国列车上过一夜怎么样  亲爱的
How about a night out, my dear, on Snowpiercer?
看样子你需要一杯茶
Looks like you could use a cup of tea.
三个崭新的转向架引擎
Three brand new bogie motors,
-那么多地方偏偏在阿拉斯加搞到  -是啊
- procured in the middle of Alaska of all places. - Yep.
我应该都校准好了
All right, think I'm all calibrated.
温度  湿度  风速和晴雨表
I've got temperature, humidity, windspeed, and barometer.
很好
Good.
放进去
And in you go.
她已经过去三天了  哈维
She's been out there for three days, Javi.
我知道
I know, man.
她建立起了系统
She's got the systems up.
她多半在那
She's probably just waiting there,
暖暖和和  舒舒服服地等待数据
all warm and cozy, for the data.
那么
So...
他想在他的夜车里过一夜
He wants an evening out in his Night Car.
你一直在搪塞这个谈话
You've been putting off this conversation,
所以我能猜到你想要我做什么
so I can only guess what it is you want me to do.
你对他意义重大
You meant a lot to him.
我花了很多年试图把他洗掉
I spent years washing my hands clean of him.
你要是能理解的话我会很感激的
I'd appreciate understanding it.
我18岁的时候  我已经是个高级妓女
When I was 18, I was already a high-end escort.
在芝加哥陪最有权势的男人女人参加私人派对
Private parties for the most powerful men and women in Chicago.
这些派对会持续很多天
They would go on for days, these parties,
都在他的列车上
and they were all on his trains.
你得知道
You need to know--
多年来
I was his exclusively
我只属于他一个人
for years.
酬劳丰厚  但我失去了一切
It paid in gold, but I lost everything,
现在你却叫我重新打开潘多拉的魔盒
and now you're asking me to reopen Pandora's box?
如果你能让他听你的  博得他的信任
If we had you in his ear to gain his trust,
掌控他  我们所有人都会帮你
to steer him, we will help you--all of us.
这就是我们现在的大业  奥德丽
This is the cause now, Audrey.
我会去做  但不是为了你们任何一个
I'll do it, but not for any of you,
也不是为了科学或梅兰妮的任务
not for the science or Melanie's mission.
而是为了我自己
This one's for me.
给尊贵的约瑟夫·威尔福德的邀请函
An invitation to the esteemed Joseph Wilford.
"特此邀请您和雪国列车极其工程师团队
"You are hereby invited to a celebration of science
一同参加科学庆典"
with Snowpiercer and their team of engineers."
有点过火了吧
A bit much, isn't it?
他们只是要发射气球
They're launching a balloon,
又不是洲际导弹
not an intercontinental ballistic missile.
他们要一份宾客名单
They're asking for a guest list.
代表你得邀请其中一些工作人员
Which means you would have to invite some of the crew.
不会吧  我真得邀请吗
Oh, fiddlesticks. Do I really?
-是的  所以我们才在这里  -嗯
- Yes, it's what we're here for. - Yeah.
-"雪国列车"  -达布斯不行
- "Snowpiercer." - Not Dubs.
他拖着我们环绕世界一圈又一圈
He's actually been dragging us around and around the world
拼命寻找他的情人
in desperate search of his paramour.
别说那个词
Don't say that word!
她是一首诗  懂吗
She's a poem, you hear me?
有魔法的优雅之鸟
Witchy bird of grace
承载着列车的灵魂
that holds the soul of the train.
她是一把钥匙
She's a key.
你们想不想和我一起夺取雪国列车
Do you want to seize Snowpiercer in your fists with me or not?
-想  -我们想
- Yes. - We do.
很好
Good.
我打算穿那件丝锦缎西装
Well, I was thinking of wearing my silk brocade suit
搭配褶边衬衫  这样应该挺帅气
and my ruffle shirt. Thought that might be nice.
一点小东西就能带给人们快乐
Takes so little for people to be so happy.
别毁了这一刻
Don't ruin it.
这是我七年来
This is the most delicious thing
-吃过的最美味的东西  -更好的还在后头
- I've tasted in seven years. - It gets better.
各位  你们很有耐心
My good people, you have been so patient.
不不  不用站起来
No, no, no, please-- please be seated.
我承诺过你们新鲜水果和蔬菜
I promised you fresh fruit and vegetables.
这是你们应得的
You've earned them.
但我还承诺了你们别的东西  不是吗
But I promised you something else, didn't I?
供你们伸展腿脚的1001节车厢
1,001 cars to stretch your legs!
今晚我将履行这诺言
And tonight I'm gonna fulfill that pledge!
没错  你们的名字都在这顶帽子里
Yes, all of your names are inside this hat.
威尔福德先生会选出三位工作人员
Mr. Wilford will select three crew members
到雪国列车玩乐一晚
for a night out on Snowpiercer.
第一位幸运赢家是...
Our first lucky winner is...
油商鲍勃  来吧  鲍勃
Oiler Bob! Come on, Bobby!
第二位无畏冒险家...
Our second intrepid adventurer...
别慌  你会被选中
Don't freak out. You'll be one of the names.
-天啊  我爱你  -...是达米安·何
- Oh, my God, I love you. - Is Damien Ho!
我喜欢你的风格  孩子
I like the cut of your jib, son.
我宾客名单上的第三位  也是最后一位
And the third and final name on my guest list is...
-是我们的女裁缝艾美莉亚  -老天啊
- Our seamstress Emelia! - Oh, my goodness!
-来吧  -天啊  是我
- Come on! - Oh, my goodness, it's me.
她实至名归  实至名归
She deserves it! She deserves it!
好样的  艾美莉亚
Well done. Well done, Emelia!
威尔福德宾客名单上那三人我都不认识
Wilford's guest list is three names I don't recognize.
里面有谁是我们能策反的吗
Is there anybody on that list we can turn to our advantage?
我会查一下档案
All right, I'll take them to the notary.
如果他们当初有雪国列车的票
If they were ticketed on Snowpiercer,
-我们就会有记录  -很好  本
- we'll have records. - Good. Ben.
今晚我们将首次和梅兰妮联系
Tonight we'll make first contact with Melanie.
别忘了今晚的真正目的
Let's not forget that's what this evening's all about.
没错  就是和宾客分享充满希望的信息
Yes, it's a hopeful message to share with our guests.
通过庆祝任务的第一步
By celebrating the mission's first step,
我们让他们知道这项事业不容置疑
we make this endeavor undeniable to them,
威尔福德必须合作  不能逃避
and Wilford's cooperation has to be inescapable.
要是我们带威尔福德来这了
What happens if we bring Wilford up here
-梅兰妮却没消息呢  -她必须联系上我们
- and we don't hear from Melanie? - She has to make contact.
我同意
Agreed.
我们这是放胆一试
This is our leap of faith.
我们想打入他的组员
We want to make inroads with his crew,
让他们看到自由的面貌
show them what freedom looks like
这样威尔福德就不能妖魔化我们
so that Wilford can't demonize us.
他也会对我们做同样的事
He'll be doing the same thing to us--
勾引我们的人
seducing our crew.
他会试着策反这房间里的所有人
He'll try and turn everyone in this room.
他的魔爪已经伸向了我们中的一些人
He's already got his hooks in some of us.
如果你指我  可以直接说出来
If you're referring to me, just come out and say it.
不  我是说任何之前就认识他的人
No, I mean anyone who knew him before--
他亲自雇的人
anyone he hired personally.
那好  我在他的安保队里工作了四年
Yeah, well, I worked security detail for the man for four years.
还有别人给威尔福德先生工作过吗
Anyone else work for Mr. Wilford?
在场的人需要信任彼此
This circle has got to trust each other.
我需要你给威尔福德先生
Now, I need you to give Mr. Wilford
提供一个他在雪国列车上最完美的夜晚
the greatest night he has ever had aboard Snowpiercer.
这是乘客服务部最大的心愿
Hospitality would like nothing more.
很好  那我们上演好戏吧
Good, then let's put on a show.
我只是
I just...
我看到那么多脸
I saw all those faces.
让我意识到我们剩下的人不多了
It just hit me how few of us are left.
死了这么多人
How many we've lost.
但我还在
But here I still am...
苟延残喘着
barely a scratch.
我们都会问为什么  贝丝
We all ask why, Bess.
你还在为什么奋斗
What do you still stand for?
我曾经知道如何辨别真假
I used to know what was true or wasn't...
我属于哪里
Where I belonged.
如今我孤身一人
Now I have no one.
只有这个
It's just this...
我们还有三千人呢
Hey, hey, there's 3,000 of us left.
雪国列车上只有2747人了
2,747 on Snowpiercer.
其实是2746人
Actually, it's-- it's 46.
-昨天有个厨师长死了  -对
- A mess chef died yesterday. - Yeah.
我们死了数十亿同胞  贝丝
Billions of souls have left us, Bess.
因为幸存者所剩无几  让我们的内疚更久无法忍受
It's because we're so few that the survivor's guilt feels unbearable.
你不是一个人
You're not alone.
好  你们跟我一起来吧
All right, would you like to follow me?
好了  我看看
All right, okay.
-太神奇了  不痛了  -你瞧
- Oh, oh, oh, that's amazing. - You see?
患者立即就能感到药效
The patient feels almost instant relief.
它究竟是怎么工作的
What does it do exactly?
这是水凝胶基的生物材料
It's a hydrogel based biomate--
这个完成了
All done here.
二等厢医疗室还有一位患者
We have one more patient up in the Second Class clinic.
这边走
Right this way.
我去就行
I got this one.
我知道你要带他们去见谁
Um, I know who you're taking them to see.
乘客服务部需要送他们去
Hospitality needs to escort them.
-非常严重  -确实
- Oh, it's very serious. - Serious indeed.
-她需要定制的植皮  -去除血栓  让血流通过
- She'd need custom grafting. - Clot busters for blood flow.
她得去我们的实验室
Well, she'll have to come back to our lab.
你的实验室在大爱丽丝上吗
Is your lab on Big Alice?
无菌病房  禁止探访
Sterile recovery, absolutely no visitors.
我们能谈谈吗
Can we have a moment?
-梅兰妮不理解  -你在说什么
- Melanie doesn't understand. - What are we talking about?
你的安德烈·莱顿
Your Andre Layton.
梅兰妮说我应该信任他
Melanie tells me that I should trust him,
但是他不信任我
but it's him that doesn't trust me.
-他根本不知道我工作有多努力  -我知道
- He has no idea how hard I work. - I do.
你知道所有乘客的名字
You know every passenger by name,
所有车厢  所有协会
every class, every guild.
所有角落和缝隙
Every nook and every cranny.
虽然我敬佩威尔福德先生
And just because I admire Mr. Wilford,
但那不意味着
that doesn't mean...
不意味着我不忠诚  我对列车忠心耿耿
That I'm disloyal. I am loyal to the train.
他在排挤我
He's pushing me out.
他在排挤我的整个部门
He's pushing out my department.
或许我们可以互相帮助
Maybe we could help each other.
你觉得我加入乘客服务部怎么样
What do you think about me joining Hospitality?
继续说
Go on.
你觉得我该担心吗
Do you think I should be worried?
威尔福德知道我是谁吗
Does Wilford know who I am?
我觉得冻伤疗法出现的太及时  不像是巧合
I think frostbite therapy is too good of a coincidence.
他们怎么可能已经对我们了解这么多了呢
Well, how could they know that much about us already?
我们的名字不在最初的乘客名单列表上
Our names weren't on the original manifest.
露丝吗
Ruth?
不  不是露丝  暂时不是
No, not Ruth. Not yet.
-疗法有用吗  -似乎有用
- Does the therapy work? - It seems to.
海德伍德夫妇在实验室做的事
What the Headwoods are doing on the ship back there,
增强人们的耐寒能力
augmenting people for cold resistance.
你会太孤立了
You'd be too isolated.
看着我  莱顿  正视我
Look at me, Layton, properly.
你一直没正视过我  我在这里不会复原的
You haven't been. I'm not going to recover here.
乔茜
Josie.
至少我可以在后面帮忙
At least I could be of use back there.
你需要人看着他们  不是吗
You need eyes on them, don't you?
我会尽所能查清楚的
I'll find out everything that I can.
我知道你让派克
And I know you've got Pike
在边境搞些小动作
cooking something at the border.
如果今晚按计划进行
Yeah, if tonight goes as planned,
我们应该会建立起一条运输路线
we should have a pipeline.
那...
Well, then...
利用起来吧
let's use it.
这是什么
What is this?
就这些
It's what you get.
你说你要把你全部的货给我
You said you were gonna bring all your product to me.
不  我没这么说过
No, I didn't say that.
是你说的
You said that after you said
在你说你不喜欢做车尾的生意之后说的
you don't like being seen doing business with the tail!
好吧  小点声  别激动
All right, keep it down, relax.
有传言说威尔福德又要去前列车厢
There's a rumor Wilford's coming uptrain again.
在夜车办一个盛大的宴会
Big event in the Night Car,
所以我会收下大麻  价格不会亏你
so I'll take the weed and a good price?
你有什么
What you got?
好吧
All right.
给
There.
更多的《大英百科全书》  棒
More Britannicas, nice.
特伦斯  清洁部受到了地缘政治的迫害
You know, Terence, Janitorial has become a geopolitical casualty.
车尾变成了有钱人的新运输路线
The tail is the new pipeline of riches.
也许叫你的清洁工快点帮我运货
Maybe get your mop jockeys to move that quickly for me,
下次我会多给你一点
and I'll give you a little more weight next time.
叫你的人住手
Tell your people to stop.
不是我做的
I did not do that.
如果你利用车尾去参与威尔福德的游戏
If you use the Tail in your Wilford game,
我们不会放过你的
we'll come for you.
我这有400人  你只有十个人
I've got 400 to your 10.
那你面对将不止是维修队的人
Then you will meet more than just Breachmen.
我们的人远不止这几个
There are many, many more of us
而他们就在你的眼皮底下
right under your little nose.
维修队的人到达
Breachmen incoming.
夜车里是什么样的  艾莉克斯
What's the Night Car like, Alex?
听说是个窑子
I heard it's a brothel.
我觉得更像夜总会
I think it's more like a cabaret.
那里什么都有
They're gonna have everything.
芒果
Mangoes.
-很兴奋吧  -是的  先生
- Excited, are we? - Yes, sir.
我先说清楚
Well, get this straight.
今晚对我很重要
This is my night--
让我有机会见到老熟人
a chance for me to meet up with old acquaintances
希望能见到梅兰妮的气球
and hopefully see Melanie's balloon
在他们面前爆炸
pop in their faces, all right?
小菜一碟
Easy-peasy.
大家都把蝴蝶结系好了吗
Everybody got their top buttons done up?
盛大的夜晚即将开始  我们走
Time for your big night out. Come on, come on!
车尾人群殴波吉  估计是替莱茨报仇
The Tailies jumped Boki. Payback for Lights, I guess.
他说他们想要杀他
He claims they tried to kill him.
如果四个车尾人想要杀一个维修工
If four Tailies wanted to kill a Breachman,
-他早就死了  -看看这些破东西
- he would be dead. - Look at this shit.
车尾人拿着这些东西在前列车厢里徘徊
Okay, we got Tailies wandering around uptrain with these.
莱顿  我们必须自保
Layton, we gotta protect ourselves, man.
现在没人需要在市场里公开携带武器
No one needs to open carry in the market right now!
这边真是乱套了
Going crazy over here.
我和你说了交给我
Hey, I told you I'd take care of it.
波吉  你有见过威尔福德吗
Boki, you ever meet Wilford?
有  十四岁的时候第一次见到他
Da, first when I was 14--
替他在塞尔维亚造桥
building bridges for him in Serbia.
所以你算是终身都从事一种工作了
Guess that makes you a lifer then?
很自豪地说是的
Proud to say it does.
住手
Come on.
-你怎么回事  -脚下打滑了
- What is wrong with you? - My foot slipped, all right?
你无法确定这人是切人手指的那人吗
Hey, you don't know that guy's the finger chopper.
你这是干什么
The hell was that?
我有一个威尔福德问题
Look, I have a Wilford problem.
不管是不是维修工干的
Whether the Breachman did it or not,
他在这里有内应
he's got support up here,
今晚他会去前列车厢
and he's coming uptrain tonight.
你有多想波吉举着三根手指
How much do you want Boki hanging around
到处转  把大家都给惹毛
waving three fingers and riling everybody up.
我可以以军事管制扣押他
I can hold him under martial law.
如果你想的话  无限期
Oh, indefinitely if you want.
好  把波吉关进禁闭室
Okay, so throw Boki in the brig,
把其他人限制在营房里  但我告诉你
confine the rest to quarters, but I'm telling you
情况没这么简单
there's something deeper going on here.
我知道  我知道时代在变
I know. I know times are changing.
但不管我发生什么
But whatever happens to me,
车尾需要支持莱顿
the Tail needs to stand by Layton.
乔茜  我们有东西给你
Josie, we have something for you.
迈尔斯
Miles.
我不想你来的
I-I didn't want you to come.
我不在乎  妈  你是我的英雄
I don't care, Mom. You're my hero.
猜猜他在管理什么  生命系统
Guess what he's engineering. Life systems.
我想成为回到外面的首批殖民者
I want to be one of the first colonists to be back outside.
你保持这个希望  迈尔斯
You hold on to that hope, Miles.
好了
Right.
准备好了
Ready.
就这样
That's it.
你紧张吗
Are you nervous?
我只是很担心奥德丽
I'm just worried about Audrey.
我会支持她
I'll have her back...
以及你
and yours.
不
Hey--oh, no.
-不不不  -要
- No, no, no. - Oh, yes.
我加入乘客服务部了
I'm joining Hospitality.
露丝是想利用你来影响我
Ruth is just using you to influence me.
那是我的主意  不是她的
It was my idea, not hers.
这样我就能盯着她
This way I can keep an eye on her.
我想你不该插手
I think you should stay out of it.
-你需要她  -不是第一次听说了
- You need her. - Yeah, so I've been told.
-谢谢  -那就听话  让我帮忙
- Thank you. - Then listen and let me help.
真典型
Typical.
我们离出发就几分钟了
We're minutes away from being able to leave,
而你却改变一切
and you go and change everything.
什么  我只变了服装
What? All I changed was the outfit.
嗯  蓝绿色  不适合你
Yeah, teal, it's not your color.
既然我们已经不在一起了
Since we're not together anymore,
你好像没资格这么说
I'm not sure you really get to say that.
-嗯  -另一边
- Oh, yeah-- - Do the other one.
相信我
Trust me.
我看看  好多了
Let's see. Much better.
人民代表
Man of the people.
我忘了你很擅长这个
I forgot you were really good at this.
不客气
You're welcome.
-谢谢  -准备好了吗
- Thank you. - Ready?
女士们先生们  闲话少说
Ladies and gentlemen, without further ado,
掌声有请威尔福德先生和他的组员
I present Mr. Wilford and his crew.
威尔福德  威尔福德
Wilford, Wilford!
很高兴见到你们
Good to see you all.
非常感谢  谢谢大家
Thank you very much. Thank you all.
-给您的  -谢谢
- For your area. - Thank you very much.
他来了
There he is.
莱顿先生
Mr. Layton.
威尔福德先生  我们欢迎你和你的组员
Mr. Wilford, we welcome you and your crew
见证对我们具有历史意义的希望一刻
to this historic moment of hope for our people.
请把你们的注意力
If I could direct all of your attention
转移到我们的工程师身上
towards our engineers.
-好了  -准备好了吗
- All right. - Good?
好了
We're good.
大家晚上好
Good evening, everyone.
今晚  我们将会发射我们的第一个气象气球
Tonight, we'll be launching the first weather balloon
它将会把数据传给我们的梅兰妮·卡维尔
that will transmit data to our own Melanie Cavill.
本
Ben.
一旦气球到达高度
Once the balloon reaches height,
也就是大约在75分钟后  梅兰妮会连接上
which is in about 75 minutes, Melanie will link to it,
然后我们将听到一个信号
and we'll hear a signal.
那个砰砰声会暗示梅兰妮安全
That ping will indicate that Melanie is safe
以及我们的任务开始
and that our mission is underway.
我觉得不会有砰砰声
I say there won't be a ping.
有人想打赌吗
Anyone taking wagers?
看样子我们已经进入发射模式
It looks like we're in launch mode now
将由哈维负责
and Javi will do the honors.
好  发射倒计时
Okay, we're launching
三  二  一
in three, two, one.
我们很快就会回来给你们汇报进展
We'll be back in a short while to update you with our progress.
谢谢
Thank you.
快穿好衣服
Better finish dressing.
威尔福德在等着呢
Wilford awaits.
我以前总是让他等
I always made him wait.
你确定你想这么做吗  还来得及打退堂鼓
You sure you want to do this? There's still time to back out.
我确定  你能把这个拿给他吗
I'm sure. Will you take this out to him?
扎拉  我和他进去后
Zarah, when I get him in there,
如果我在30分钟后没出来  进来找我
if I'm not out in 30 minutes, come get me.
谢谢
Thank you.
看样子你们劫掠了我的酒窖
I see you've raided my cellar.
99年份的武戈伯爵酒庄生产
'99 Vogue Musigny Vieilles Vignes.
朋友吗  我们现在正在穿越
My friends, we are now crossing
阿拉斯加和西伯利亚之间的白令海峡大桥
the Great Bering Strait Bridge between Alaska and Siberia.
在威尔福德先生建起这座桥之前
Until Mr. Wilford built this bridge,
这两个海岸在上个冰川期后
those two shores had not been connected
就没有连接过
since the last ice age.
所以在我们穿越冰冻海洋的同时
So as we roll atop the frozen ocean,
让我们为威尔福德先生举杯
let us all raise a glass to Mr. Wilford.
-干杯  -敬威尔福德先生
- Here, here. - To Mr. Wilford.
谢谢  谢谢  谢谢
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
谢谢大家  干杯
Thank you, cheers.
莱顿先生  你的旅程很令人着迷
Mr. Layton, your journey has been a fascinating one.
从偷渡者到叛军领袖再到掌管我的列车
From stowaway to rebel leader to the running of my train.
恕我直言  这不是你的列车
All due respect, it's not your train.
你好  约瑟夫
Hello, Joseph.
奥德丽小姐
Miss Audrey.
好久不见
It's been a long time.
你能光临真好
Dashing of you to drop in.
你洗漱过了吗
Are you brushed and watered?
我有此意
I intend to be.
来吧
Mm, come.
我带你看看我对这里做了什么
Let me show you what I've done with the place.
乐意至极
There's nothing I'd like more.
靠近点
Come closer.
看看岁月对你做了什么
Let me see what the years have done to you.
你变了
You're different.
严寒改变了我们所有人  包括夜车
The freeze changed us all, the Night Car too.
怎么说
How?
我对她做了改造
I made her into something new.
仍然是游乐场
It's still a playground,
但不再致力于个人快感
but not so much for individual pleasure.
完全没有快感
No pleasure at all.
我给你展示下
Let me show you.
这辆列车上的每个人
Every single person on this train
都受到了创伤
is traumatized.
我试图帮他们找到安宁
I try and help them find peace.
我们可以互相倾诉我们失去了什么
We can be frank with each other about what we lost.
我从没失去过任何东西
I never lose anything.
一点遗憾没有吗  约瑟夫
No regrets at all, Joseph?
人人都在为拯救你而伤心
Everyone's grieving save you.
我为失去你七年而伤心
I grieve losing you for seven years.
这种经历需要你敞开心扉
This experience requires you to open your heart.
让我进去
Let me in.
你能做到吗
Can you do that?
到底怎么回事
What is going on exactly?
性感尤物
Sticky, little honeypot?
那取决于他们  露丝
That's up to them, Ruth.
他们在发射下个气象气球前还有40分钟
They got 40 minutes till the next act with the weather balloon.
让那些人保持满意
Keep those ones happy.
还要酒吗
More wine?
我去  你是澳大利亚人吗
Holy shit, are you Aussie?
是的  正宗的  我是最后一个澳大利亚人
Yeah, fair dinkum. I'm the last Aussie.
不  伙计  我才是最后一个
Nah, mate, I'm the last Aussie.
什么  真的吗
What, really?
是真的  Z  她是澳大利亚的
Shit, it's truth, Z. She's from Aus.
不会吧
No way.
-我是默里  -艾美莉亚
- I'm Murray. - Emelia.
艾美莉亚  你不是悉尼的吧
Emelia--hey, you're not from Sydney, are you?
-不  我是珀斯的  -你是珀斯的
- No, I'm from Perth. - You're from Perth?
我是西部的
She's a western girl.
还需要什么吗
Anything else I can get you?
很多东西  不过再来一杯就好
Mm, so many things, but I'll settle for another.
我记得你  小莱拉
I remember you-Lilah Junior.
是LJ   我也记得你
It's LJ. I remember you too.
你是梅兰妮女儿  你之前真是个呆子
You're Melanie's daughter. You were such a dork.
你之前真是个婊子
You were such a bitch.
准确
Accurate.
来吧
Come on.
我本应该在雪国列车上负责洗衣的
I was supposed to be on the laundry on Snowpiercer,
但它没等我们上去就离开了
but it left without us.
你在大爱丽丝上是洗衣的吗
Is that what you do on Big Alice?
我不该说的
I'm not supposed to say.
你们在那边还好吗
You guys all right over there?
嗯  我们很好
Yeah, we're all good.
我或许有办法能保持联系
I might have a way to keep in touch.
给
Here.
是什么
What are they?
是我的幸运护目镜
They're my lucky goggles.
你拿去吧
You take 'em.
你在你们的列车上戴着  有人会联系你的
You wear 'em on your train, and someone will contact you.
快来
Come on.
做清洁工最棒的地方在于
Best part about being a janitor...
你可以去任何地方
Is you get to go everywhere.
我带了礼物
I brought presents.
《不列颠百科全书》
An Encyclopedia Britannica.
W条目下  有长毛猛犸象
W, which has wooly mammoth--
超厉害  灭绝了
totally badass, totally extinct.
还有
And...
告诉我你看到了什么
Tell me what you see.
有跳舞
There's dancing.
我能听到乐队演奏
I can hear a band playing
还有你的声音
and your voice in my ear.
告诉我你还体验到了什么
Tell me what else you're experiencing.
不
No.
你让我割自己的手腕
You made me cut my own wrists.
但我救了你
But I saved you.
-我想要  奥德丽  -不
- I want it, Audrey. - No.
求你了  我很需要
Please, I need it.
我需要你
I need you.
只有你  只有你  奥德丽
You're the only one. You're the only one, Audrey.
我需要
I need it.
我想要  我想要
I want it. I want it.
是火车头发出的五分钟警报
That's five minute warning from the engine.
五分钟警报
Five minute warning.
我的父母在战争中跟170多人
My parents froze to death with, like, 170 other people
一起被冻死了  所以我妈妈可能在某个...
in the war, so my mom is probably somewhere like--
你想她吗
Do you miss her?
这世上的每个人几乎都是
Literally everybody in the world
冻死的  所以
froze to death, so...
我最近才开始重新了解我的妈妈
Well, I just got around to even knowing my mom again,
她现在坐上了金雪橇
and now she's off on a gold sled,
我猜她也在哪个冰天雪地的地方这样吧
so guess she's somewhere freezing doing this.
但是威尔福德毕竟把你养大了
But Wilford, he raised you, though, right?
嗯
Yeah.
他肯定不喜欢听我说这些话
He would hate to hear me saying this,
但是我以前也不知道
but I just didn't know I was gonna care
我会这么在乎梅兰妮
about Melanie this much.
你看到上面那些闪光点了吗
Hey, see up there, that flashing light?
-那是她的气球吗  -是的
- Isn't that her balloon? - Yeah, it is.
也许她也能看到
Maybe she can see it too.
我们肯定到了她向上传输的高度
We must be at the altitude for her uplink.
我该走了
I should probably go.
我们还是别做朋友了
Let's not be friends.
绝对是敌人
Total enemies.
就现在
Right now.
不好意思  谢谢  威尔福德在哪里
Excuse me, thank you. Where is Mr. Wilford?
马上要开始了  他再不来要赶不上了
It's about to start. He's going to miss it.
-奥德丽没事吧  -她没事
- Is Audrey okay? - She's fine.
他们应该要来了
They're coming, I think.
你兴奋吗  艾莉珊德拉
Are you excited, Alexandra?
重要的一刻要来了
It's a big moment.
威尔福德觉得她已经死了
Wilford thinks she's dead already.
你觉得呢
What do you think?
我觉得如果能有人
I think that if there's one person
在外面存活  那肯定是她
that could survive out there, maybe it's her.
没错
That's right.
-你们好  -你来了  先生
- Oh, goodie. - There you are, sir.
前面给你准备好了位置
Got a seat for you right up front.
重头戏终于要开始了
Finally, the main event.
万众期待的倒计时
The countdown we've all been waiting for.
-欢迎回来  先生  -谢谢  莱顿
- Welcome back, sir. - Thanks, Layton.
雪国列车驾驶舱向你们问好
Hello again from the cockpit of Snowpiercer.
请各位都做好历史的见证者
Please take your own front seat to history.
我们的气象气球已经升至34000米
Our weather balloon is at 34,000.
34700米
700 meters.
等升至35000米  梅兰妮就会建立连接
Once it hits 35,000, Melanie should link to it
开始收集采集到的气象数据
and start collecting all of its weather data.
这是她寻找可以
The first step in her finding
重新生存地带的第一步
where we can start recolonization.
看
Here we go.
我们已经升至34800米
We are at 34,800.
34850米
850.
抱歉
Sorry.
35000米
35,000 meters.
35100米
35,100.
35150米
150.
35200米
200.
35250米
250.
太好了  太好了
Yes, yes, yes!
太好了
Yes!
太好了  梅兰妮  太好了
Yes, Melanie, yes!
你和威尔福德刚刚是怎么回事
What was that between you and Wilford?
我和你说过会发生什么事的
I told you what could happen.
我应该担心你吗
Should I be worried?
相信我  他现在完全被我们掌控
Trust me. He's exactly where we want him.